Walt Kuhn Family Papers and Armory Show
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Walt Kuhn Family Papers, 1859-1978, Series 4:; (Box 3-26, 32-35, OV 39-55; 25.8 linear feet)
  - General Correspondence, 1890-1966, 4.3:; (Box 5-9, 32, OV 40; 4 linear feet)
    Pressoir, E.E.: 1928 (Guggenheim application), 1932 (2 letters)
    Price, Frederic Newlin (Ferargil Galleries): 1948 (3 letters)
    Prior, Harris K. (American Federation of Arts): 1957
    Purnell, Lewis M.: 1943
    Putnam, Samuel: 1928 (2 letters)
    Quinn, John (see also Watson): 1919, 1920, 1921 (5 letters)
    Quinton, Cornelia B. Sage (California Legion of Honor): 1928
    Randolph, Lee F. (California School of Fine Arts): 1930, 1942 (2 letters)
    Raseman, Richard P. (Cranbrook Academy of Art): 1940
    Rathbone, Perry T.: 1946
    Reber, Gottlieb Friedrich: 1931, 1932, 1933, undated (3 letters)
    Redmond, Johnston: 1933
    Renne, Otto A.: 1935, 1936, 1938, 1940 (5 letters; see also Carr)
    Renwick, Charles S. Jr.: 1945-1946 (2 letters)
    Rickey, George: 1937
    Ringling Brothers and Barnum and Bailey (see Butler and North)
    Rivière, Nina S. (Toledo Museum of Art): 1932
    Robinson, Edward G.: 1936 (2 letters)
    Roché, H.P.: 1928, 1938, 1939 (7 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Rogers, Christopher H. (regarding Francis Rogers): 1930
    Rogers, Jane: 1932
    Rogers, Meyric (Art Institute of Chicago): 1948 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Rogers, Will: [1926]
    Roosevelt, Jean S. (Mrs. Philip James): 1928
    Rosenberg, Paul (Paul Rosenberg and Co.): 1942, 1946, 1948 (8 letters)
    Ross, Leola: 1928, 1931, 1935, 1936, 1937 (5 items including Christmas cards)
    Rossiter, Henry P.: 1928
    Rothschild, Howard: 1927
    Roullier, Alice F. (Arts Club of Chicago): 1925, 1927, 1933, 1941 (8 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Rousseau, Théodore: 1935
    Rumsey, Mary H. (Mrs. C.C.): 1930, 1934-1936, 1938, 1940, 1945, 1949, undated (11 items including Christmas card and receipts for paintings sold)
    Ryan, Beatrice Judd (Beaux Arts Galerie): 1928, 1929 (4 letters)
    Saint-Gaudens, Homer (Carnegie Institute): 1931, 1933, 1940, 1946-1949 (18 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Saklatwalla, Ann: 1944-1945 (2 letters; see also Provenance Files, "Bareback Rider")
    Saklatwalla, B.D.: 1928, 1930-1936, 1941 (2 letters, 7 Christmas cards containing prints, 1931 print signed Jean Crotti)
    Salinger, Jehanne Bietry: 1928-1930, 1933, 1935, 1946-1948 (includes signed print by Harry Wickey; 17 letters)
    Salons of America: 1923, 1924
    Salpeter, Harry (Esquire): 1936-1938 (6 letters)
    Sanborn, Robert Alden: 1945
    Sands, Mary (Museum of Modern Art): 1930
    Sanger, Helen: 1948-1950, 1953, 1963 (16 letters)
    Sanger, Margaret (American Birth Control League, Inc.): 1928
    Santa Barbara Museum of Art (see Bear, Steele, Story; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Santo, Patsy: 1937-1946, 1948-1949, 1953 (103 letters, some illustrated)
    Sardi Gina, Anne (Marie Harriman Gallery): 1941-1942, 1947, 1949 (6 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files and Provenance Files, "Girl in Shako" and "Guide")
    Schlesigner, Louis: 1949
    Schmit, Waldo (Smithsonian Institution): 1936-1949
    Schulte, Antoinette: 1932-1938 (8 items, including Christmas card with original print)
    Seiberling, Frank Jr. (Toledo Museum of Art): 1943, 1946 (3 letters)
    Seymour Halpern Associates: 1945
    Shapiro, Meyer: 1938
    Sharkey, Alice M. (Whitney Museum of American Art): 1944
    Shaw, Marjorie: 1930 (Christmas card with woodblock print)
    Sheeler, Charles: 1938 (See also Series 4.2: Walt Kuhn Letters to Family)
    Shostac, Percy (Labor Division, Greater New York Fund): 1941
    Shyrock, Burnett H.: 1938 (4 letters)
    Siple, Walter H. (Cincinnati Art Museum): 1938, 1942, 1945 (4 letters)
    Skeoch, Mary E.: 1934-1936, 1938 (8 letters)
    Skira, Alfred: 1932 (5 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files, 1933)
    Smith, Adele (Studio House, Philips Memorial Gallery, Museum of Modern Art Gallery of Washington): 1935, 1938, 1939 (5 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Smith, Cecil: 1937-1938 (3 letters)
    Smith, Gordon M. (Currier Gallery of Art): 1950
    Smoluchowska, Donia (Arden Gallery, Marie Harriman Gallery): 1929, 1932 (3 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Snow, Carmel (Harper's Bazaar): 1935, 1941 (2 letters)
    Spaeth, Eloise (Mrs. Otto L.; Dayton Art Institute, American Federation of Arts, The Guild Hall): 1943-1953, 1960, undated (50 letters)
    Spaeth, Otto: 1943 (4 letters)
    Spier, LaSalle (brother of Vera Kuhn): 1914-1963
    Spingarn, Amy (Mrs. Joel Elias): 1938 (2 letters)
    Sprague, Marshall (Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center): 1948 (2 letters)
    Steele, Mary Oldfield (Santa Barbara Museum of Art): 1953-1954 (4 letters)
    Stendahl, E.L. (Stendahl Art Galleries): 1939 (3 letters)
    Stetson, Carroll: 1932
    Stickney, Dorothy (Mrs. Howard Lindsay): 1941
    Stinson, Eugene: 1928
    Story, Ala (Santa Barbara Museum of Art): 1954 (2 letters)
    Stout, George L.: 1952
    Strain, Gertrude: 1935
    Stransky, Joseph: 1927
    Strater, Henry (Museum of Art of Ogonquit): 1953-1954 (4 letters)
    Stroh, Earl W.: 1942 (2 letters)
    Studio House (see Gates, Law, Smith)
    Swartz, Susan (Art Institute of Zanesville, Ohio): 1943-1944 (7 letters)
    Swope, Herbert Bayard: 1949
    Sykes, Maltby (Alabama Polytechnic Institute): 1946
    Taggard, Genevieve: 1930, 1931, 1933, 1941, undated (13 letters)
    Tanner, Ethel: 1930 (Christmas card with woodblock print)
    Taylor, Bertrand: 1945
    Taylor, Francis Henry (Metropolitan Museum of Art): 1949 (see also Provenance Files, "Blue Clown")
    Taylor, Henry White: 1938
    Taylor, Olive (Mrs. Bertrand): 1944-1946, 1948-1949, undated (14 letters)
    Teague, Virginia (Mrs. R.L.): 1951 (2 letters)
    Teigen, Peter (Princeton University School of Architecture): 1928, 1929 (2 letters)
    Thayer, Ellen (The Dial): 1927, 1928 (2 letters)
    Thompson, Mark B.: 1934, 1935, 1937 (3 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Thorp, George G. (American Federation of Arts): 1947
    Toledo Museum of Art (see Godwin, Rivière, Seiberling)
    Toler, Sidney: 1941
    Todd, Bianca: 1929, 1933, 1934 (3 items including Christmas cards with original prints)
    Trovato, Joseph (Munson-Williams-Proctor-Institute): 1946, 1949 (2 letters)
    Tucker, Allen: 1938
    Turney, Winthrop: 1924
    Tyson, Carroll: 1934
    Underwood, Gilbert Stanley (architect): 1938, 1948 (5 letters)
    Valentiner, Dr. W.R. (Detroit Institute of Arts): 1945
    Valez, Dr. Xavier de: 1934
    Venendi, Mario: 1949 (3 letters)
    Vidar, Frede: 1936
    Vreeland, Mr. and Mrs. Francis (Toby and Marion): 1934-1938 (6 letters)
    Wadsworth, Alice (Mrs. James W.): 1940, 1941, 1942, 1945 (8 letters)
    Waida, Robert: 1928
    Waldron, James M. K. (Reading Public Museum and Art Gallery): 1936, 1937, 1961 (3 letters)
    Walker, Maynard: 1946, 1948-1949, 1951-1952, 1955, 1961 (10 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files and Provenance Files, "Guide" and "Veteran Acrobat")
    Ward, William: 1949
    Washburn, Gordon B. (Rhode Island School of Design Museum of Art): 1945
    Watkins, C. Law (Studio House, Phillips Memorial Gallery): 1933 (2 letters)
    Watson, John (for John Quinn): 1914, 1921 (2 letters), 1938
    Watson, Nan: 1928, undated
    Wear, Verna (Mortimer Brandt Gallery): 1943 (2 letters)
    Weber, Max: 1938
    Weber, W.: 1928
    Wehle, Harry B. (Metropolitan Museum of Art; see Provenance Files, "Girl in Uniform")
    Weibel, Adèle (Detroit Institute of Arts): 1938
    Weigel, Paul: 1932, 1934, 1935, 1937 (4 letters)
    Weinberger, Alfred: 1931
    Weir, Ernest and Mary: 1945 (2 letters)
    Weng, Siegfried R. (Dayton Art Institute): 1943 (2 letters)
    Werner, M.R.: 1928
    Weston, Edward: 1928-1930, 1932-1933, 1935, 1937-1938, 1941 (9 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Wetmore, Edith: 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932-1936 (16 items including Christmas cards)
    White, Frances M.: 1945
    Whiting, F.A. Jr. (Magazine of Art ): 1938
    Whitney, Harry: 1942 (see also Greason and Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Whitney Studio Galleries (see also Force): 1929
    Whitney Museum of American Art (see Force, Free, More, Freeman, Sharkey, Goodrich)
    Wilder, Mitchell A. (Colorado Springs): 1946-1953 (75 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Wilenski, R.H.: 1938, 1939, 1945-1946 (8 letters)
    Williams, Adele (Women's club of Richmond): 1930
    Williamson, Ada (Philadelphia Art Alliance): 1927, 1928, 1945, 1949 (19 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Wilmington Society of the Fine Arts (see Bissell)
    Wilson, Henry J.: 1950
    Winser, Beatrice: 1935, 1940 (7 letters)
    Woelfle, Arthur M.: 1914 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Woelfle, Georgiana: 1936, 1937, 1963 (3 letters)
    Wood, Stanley: 1928
    Zayas, Marius de: 1934, 1939, 1947, 1948 (10 letters)
    Zügel, Heinrich von: 1904
    - General Correspondence, 1890-1913, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - General Correspondence, 1914-1919 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - General Correspondence, 1920-1922 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - General Correspondence, 1923, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
    - General Correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - General Correspondence, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - General Correspondence, 1927, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
    - General Correspondence, 1928, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 26-29)
    - General Correspondence, 1929, (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 32) (Box 5, Folder 30-33)
    - General Correspondence, 1930, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - General Correspondence, 1931, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    - General Correspondence, 1932, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 7-11)
    - General Correspondence, 1933, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 12-14)
    - General Correspondence, 1934, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15-18)
    - General Correspondence, 1935, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 19-22)
    - General Correspondence, 1936, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 23-27)
    - General Correspondence, 1937, (7 folders; oversized material housed in Box 32) (Box 6, Folder 28-34)
    - General Correspondence, 1938, (12 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-12)
    - General Correspondence, 1939, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 13-18)
    - General Correspondence, 1940, (5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 32) (Box 7, Folder 19-23)
    - General Correspondence, 1941, (6 folders; oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 7, Folder 24-29)
    - General Correspondence, 1942, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 30-33)
    - General Correspondence, 1943, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 34-37)
    - General Correspondence, 1944, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
    - General Correspondence, 1945, (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 5-9)
    - General Correspondence, 1946, (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 32) (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
    - General Correspondence, 1947, (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 32) (Box 8, Folder 13-16)
    - General Correspondence, 1948, (8 folders) (Box 8, Folder 17-24)
    - General Correspondence, 1949, (8 folders) (Box 8, Folder 25-32)
    - General Correspondence, 1950, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 33-35)
    - General Correspondence, 1951, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - General Correspondence, 1952, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
    - General Correspondence, 1953, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
    - General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - General Correspondence, 1964-1966, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - General Correspondence, A-L, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - General Correspondence, M-W and Illegible, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - General Correspondence, Kuhn Fragments, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Oversized General Correspondence and Enclosures, (Oversized material scanned with Box 5, F31; Box 6, F30; Box 7, F23; Box 8, F11 and F13) (Box 32)
    - Oversized Blueprint Enclosed with General Correspondence, (Oversized material from Box 7, F24) (Box OV 40)
  - Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files, 1920-1966, 4.4:; (Box 9-10, OV 41; 1.5 linear feet)
    This series contains a variety of materials relating to exhibitions and sales of Walt Kuhn's artwork between 1920 and 1958. Files for the Harriman and Durand-Ruel galleries also document selected exhibits of other artists and other activities of these galleries.
    Documentation for exhibitions that took place in the 1920s is sparse; included are catalogs, announcements, inventories, and receipts for exhibitions at M. de Zayas Gallery, Montross Gallery, Beaux Arts Galerie, Grand Central Art Galleries, M. Knoedler and Co., the Arts Club of Chicago, Albert Roullier Galleries, and Anderson Galleries.
    From 1930 onwards, exhibitions are more thoroughly documented. Records of exhibitions typically include announcements, marked catalogs, guest lists, diagrams showing the arrangement of art work in the galleries, letters detailing the production of the show or responding to the show, press coverage, and summary documents showing attendance figures and sales. For some exhibitions, there are also photographs and guest books.
    Because of Kuhn's long relationship with the Marie Harriman Gallery, files contain a variety of unique materials. Included is correspondence concerning exhibits of André Derain, Pablo Picasso, and Demetrius Galanis in the early 1930s. Also found are detailed regional reports on museums and private collectors throughout the United States and their relative interest in modern art. Other items include vouchers for sales of Kuhn's artwork, a 1931 cartoon by Kuhn of himself with Marie Harriman in Europe; a photographic portrait of Harriman by Berenice Abbott and another by Underwood and Underwood; and a transcript of a 1931 radio address given by Marie Harriman.
    The series is arranged by gallery or exhibition in rough chronological order. The Western Traveling Exhibition files are further broken down by venue and arranged in the order in which the exhibition traveled.
    Additional materials relating to the galleries and exhibitions named in this series can be found elsewhere in the collection. Exhibitions before 1920 are discussed in some detail in Walt Kuhn Letters to Family from those years. Additional exhibition catalogs and announcements are found in Printed Materials, and correspondence with galleries exists in General Correspondence. See individual series descriptions for more details.
    See the Index for a list of selected correspondents from series 4.3 General Correspondence with cross-references to this series and 4.5: Provenance Files.
    This series has been scanned in entirety, with the exception of an oversized plan of the Marie Harriman Gallery.
    - Miscellaneous Galleries, 1920-1929, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1926-1927 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Downtown Gallery, 1927-1933, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1932, (7 folders) (Box 9, Folder 24-30)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1933, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 31-34)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1934, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1935, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1936, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1937, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 8-11)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1939, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1940, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1941, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
    - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1942-1943, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 41) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Durand-Ruel Galleries, 1943-1944, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
    - Durand-Ruel Galleries, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Durand-Ruel Galleries, 1945, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
    - Durand-Ruel Galleries, 1946, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 26-27)
    - Durand-Ruel Galleries, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Durand-Ruel Galleries, 1948, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Western Traveling Exhibition (Box 10)
      - Marked Catalog, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - Colorado Springs, CO, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - Colorado Springs, CO, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Colorado Springs, CO, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - San Francisco, CA, 1946-1948 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - Santa Barbara, CA, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 35)
      - Los Angeles, CA, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 36)
      - Los Angeles, CA, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 37)
      - Omaha, NE, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - Bloomfield Hills, MI, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 39)
      - Milwaukee, WI, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 40)
      - Pittsburgh, PA, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 41)
      - Syracuse, NY, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Cincinnati Art Museum Exhibition, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Albany Institute of History and Art, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - University of Arizona, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Oversized Marie Harriman Gallery Material, (Oversized material from Box 10, F20) (Box OV 41)
  - Provenance Files, 1910-1964, 4.5:; (Box 11-13, 32, OV 42-44; 2.7 linear feet)
    The Kuhns kept meticulous records of Walt Kuhn's art work. Their original file folders contain detailed annotations about paintings and sculptures, along with art reproductions, tracings, and other documentation. Annotations include information such as the model used for the work; where the work was created, exhibited, reproduced, and sold; and critical response. Some of the files also contain correspondence, clippings, exhibition catalogs, announcements, and bills of sale. Tempera paintings, watercolors, etchings, and lithographs are documented in a bound ledger filed at the end of this series.
    Occasionally files contain other unique documentation. The unusually thick file for "Still Life with Red Bananas," for example, contains printed materials related to a controversy over the 1946 international exhibition of the State Department's collection of modern art, which was cancelled in response to conservative reaction. The collection was sold as "surplus" by the War Assets Administration, and the public outcry that ensued is documented in clippings in this file.
    In addition to photographs of works of art, photographs in this series include publicity photographs of Edna St. Vincent de Millay standing before the painting "Mario" in her home and other installation views. Original sketches can be found in the files for Lahr's portrait and the paintings "Zuleika," "Absolom's House," "Beach Scene," "Green Apples with Gray Curtain," "Interior," and "Maternity." Miscellanous tracings and watercolor sketches of paintings whose original file folders are not present are filed at the end of this series.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by the the artwork's title or by a key word in the title, grouping files for clown paintings, girl paintings, pine tree paintings, etc. This arrangement has been preserved, although it is idiosyncratic. Files for individual works have been grouped together in general alphabetical files. Large files are filed and listed individually. Execution dates of artwork for some files are provided in parentheses after the file headings and should not be confused with record dates.
    Original files are very brittle and have torn edges and missing fragments. Microfilm of the collection made in 1965 may show the file before such damage occurred (reels D242A-D242B). Additional material related to the provenance of Kuhn's artwork is filed in Financial Records and elsewhere in the collection. See individual series descriptions for more details. A record book documenting Vera Kuhn's art jewelry is in Photographs and Scrapbooks.
    See the Index for a list of selected correspondents from 4.3 General Correspondence with cross-references to this series and 4.4: Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files.
    - ABS - ACR, 1916-1945 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - ACR - APP, 1921-1941, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - APP - ATH, 1927-1964, (Oversized material housed in OV 43) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Athlete in Green" (1946), 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - ATH - BER, 1919-1953, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - BLA - BLO, 1922-1946, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "The Blue Clown" (1931), 1931-1944 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "The Blue Clown" (1931), 1946-1953, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - BOU - CAM, 1918-1949 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - CAR - CLO, 1915-1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - CLO - CLO, 1929-1959 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - CLO - DOR, 1915-1938, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - DOR - EIG, 1925-1937, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - ELE - FLO, 1918-1940, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - FLO - GIR, 1921-1946, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - GIR - GIR, 1920-1942 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - GIR - GRE, 1912-1946, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - GRE - GUI, 1930-1947 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - HAR - HYD, 1915-1938, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Imaginary History" Series, 1918-1923, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Imaginary History" Series, 1918-1921, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - IND - KAN, 1921-1947, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Portrait of Burt Lahr (1947), 1947-1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - LAN - MAN, 1918-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - MAN - MAN, 1918-1947 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - MAR - MOR, 1912-1960 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - MOU - PIE, 1926-1946, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - PIN - PIN, 1918-1946 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - PIT - POT, 1919-1945, (Oversized material housed in OV 43) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - RED - ROS, 1924-1946 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - ROS - SAN, 1910-1961, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - SHE - STI, 1922-1948, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Still Life with Red Bananas" (1941), 1941-1951, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - STI - TRE, 1921-1942, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - TRE-TRI (1937-1939), 1937-1944 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Trio" (1937), 1937-1941 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "Trio" (1937), 1941-1951, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - TRU - WHI, 1922-1959, (Oversized material housed in OV 42) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - WHI - YEL, 1915-1938, (Oversized material housed in OV 42 and OV 43) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "Young Clown" (1932), 1935-1948, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - YOU-ZUL (1915, 1925-1939), 1915-1942 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Tempera, Watercolor, Etching, Lithograph Records (1915-1938), undated, (Oversized bound volume housed in Box 32) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Tracings of Artwork, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 44) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Watercolor Sketches of Paintings (1933-1942), undated (Box 13, Folder 10)